[Music]
I am yours Namaste brothers, sisters, friends, I am
very welcome to all of you in this first ever Hindi
live stream. It feels great to be present with you all. Let's
see who all are present
with us. Pritam Piyush Janga
Singh Chauhan,
Maint Yuvraj Garg Vineet
Yashveer today. Harbinjar, Doctor Dharamraj and Rajesh
Harsh Indranil, Slice Par Maint Pritpal,
Rohan Gupta, Ashish Mahi, Gaurav Riya, Jio, Gai Ne Boond Tan Me
Jatin Shikhar, Saurabh Shivaay
Shatru, Jo Yoga N X Abhishek Ching,
Vaishakh Jainul,
Devanshu Harshada Dasha Vaishakh,
Rajesh and many more. It feels great to see you all.
Thank you very much for giving us here.
As you know, this is a Hindi
podcast, Hindi live streaming. So today I will
answer all the questions
in Hindi. You
can ask me questions in any language. You can ask me something in English
too, I will answer your questions
in Hindi. So,
what are the answers, what are the questions? Let's
see what we will talk about today. Today we will
talk about history, we will
talk about science, politics, you
decide.  Ask questions and I'll answer.
Let's see what we ask. Let's ask
a somewhat interesting question. So,
Ashish's question is, how can Tibet be freed from China?
Fixed Deposit: Tibet is currently under Chinese
occupation. It has been under
Chinese occupation since around 1955, and
their hold is very strong.
China has a very strong hold on Tibet.
And today the situation is that the
majority of Chinese people in Tibet have become a
minority. So many Huns have come and
settled in the Chinese territory that Tibet has become a
minority as well. The entire
administration is in Chinese, everything, the
entire government machinery is in Chinese.
China also has many military bases in Tibet.
So, all these things mean
that
China's hold on the Home Little Butte is very
strong. So, initially, it
is very difficult to free Tibet from China.
This can only happen when the
Chinese Communist Party itself becomes independent
and their hold on China weakens.
If this situation arises,
Tibet will be freed from China.  It might be possible to free it
and if India wants peace in the northern border
and western border then
we will have to free Italy
somehow or the other. For this
we need patience, we
need patience, we will have to work slowly and patiently
or else
our own strength, India's economic
strength and military strength,
both of them will have to be strengthened a lot
more, it will have to be strengthened at
least double-triple times than it is today, only then
we can free Italy
because if our economy and
our military strength
increases a lot, only then we will be able to compete with China, so
this is a very long term plan,
I think it will take at least 20 years to complete
this entire work, Vicky, such big
works are not done in a week or two, they are not done in 12 years, it takes
time, so
we need to do this and only then perhaps we will be able to
free Italy from China. Activate
history, it has always been a part of our Greater India,
our yesterday, which is a
cultural and Shakespearean option.  Follow-up has
always been a very
important
part of it, so we need to bring it back, so for that
we will have to make ourselves stronger first.
Next question is, we have
looted and
adjusted. Let me ask some questions, how to
update, did you see a
possibility of India and travelling together
in the future?
Cooperation can happen with anyone, we can do it,
we can
operate with our full force even with our opposing enemies,
in some things like for
example, climate change is being talked about, it has become
very important these days on a
global scale, so
India and China can definitely operate on this thing, we can
work together
and on some other things also,
we can operate a lot in world trade
and there are some other things too, we can do
next, in international
relations, in international relations,
where we and China can work together, so
these are a lot of possibilities, so
this is definitely related to India and
Channel Saath Mein Kaam Kare In The Future
that Rohan Gupta asks how did the
tradition of arranged marriages come from, this is
related to the times of Islamic invasions,
so where did this tradition of arranged marriages come from,
it is a very old tradition, friend, according to me
and as old as the history of India is, I
think this is a custom of arranged marriages and in the olden times,
as you know, there used to be Swayamvar in
which girls could choose their husbands on their own,
Meena, so this was
our condition and there were other arranged marriages as well and this is
only traditional of India, it has been there all over the
world, foreign friends, but
if you go to European royalty,
if you talk about British royalty, then
if you go some 5 years back, then
who was one, oh, there was a British King, then there was this
Prince who was married to Orange,
caffeine number knowledge, when there were
opportunities princesses of some Spanish princesses,
maybe I should reach the road that maybe the
universe should be like this and what did they get in dowry,
they got in dowry  The tradition
of Mumbai, which is clear from Ireland, this thing, this
custom, this tradition is a very old tradition
and it has been the tradition of India only, it is the
tradition of the whole world in which arranged
marriages used to happen, so this
tradition is a
tradition of time rather than just a method of Islamic invasion, it is a very old
tradition, who has done proper detailed
rough research on it, it will not seem like a historical
story, but if we read
our old texts, if you
talk about Mahabharata, Ramayana, then I
think arranged marriages used to happen in them too, it is
old, very old, but Shravan
and there is nothing regressive in it, this backwaters, nothing, I think in that,
creatures were also given 24 years as far as
whom you would like to marry,
Swayamvar
is a big part of it and this other arranged
marriage is also a part, so everything was
different in our history itself,
MP3
Lut Yash asks, wide in various fields, to come
India before the 11th century
and would be seen after the 11th century,
this era of unity  Problem
Kshipra, simple things, if you talk about unity,
absolutely, if you look before the 10th century, there used to be
very united, very
powerful emperors and Maharajas,
for example, if we talk about Guptas,
you will see that their
empire was very big and full and very powerful,
for this no one had anything to
invest in India at all, after that
what happened after Gupta Pawan Gupta was that
India became politically correct, more small
kings came into existence and they all used to fight among themselves, they did
not have much power, so outsiders could come and take advantage of this thing
and hence gradually
after the 10th, 11th, 12th century,
they slowly progressed in India and they
definitely captured little by little territory
and eventfully, a lot of
Northern India and West India
came under their control, we are talking about lighter invaders and
Islamic invaders, so
it is absolutely a matter of bread
politically, if your country is yours  If the
geographical region is united then it becomes
very difficult for outsiders to attack and occupy it. If
we talk about today, even today
India is not that united. So much is talked about
only petrol and diesel.
Right now the situation is such that there are about
2030 different small countries in India, each one of which is
going separately in its own deductions. So
this is also such a situation. India's
area is such a big country, such a
big geography of the size of a subcontinent, that
if it has to remain safe, then
political unity and a very strong
political alternative is very important for it.
Without that, India's future is a bit weak. For me, it is all about
unity.
If there is no unity, then we will lose to others.
A.
Lut
and Priyansh ask what happened in the
Battle of Haldighati between Maharana Pratap
and Babar. Akbar talks to Babar Khan on English
subject. Akbar himself
was not present in Akbar's army. Akbar's proxies were there,
but what is this battle?  Haldighati
was 1 hour long, but if we look at its contents,
why it was so? At that time, Akbar
was the Jodha, he had control over the whole of India, and at that time,
he defeated many Rajputs and brought them all
into his camp. So, these Rajput
kings and Maharajas worked for Akbar
and considered Akbar as their ideal.
Maharana Pratap was one of them. He
refused to accept Akbar as his own, but he
said that he would always
remain independent and no one would rule over him.
This became
a problem for Akbar's expansion plans. So, what Akbar did was that
he dispatched some Rajputs to
either kill Maharana Pratap
or defeat him
so that Akbar could take his territory
into his own hands. Akbar's political
and military objective was to
either remove Maharana Pratap or
kill him and take his territory.
Maharana Pratap's
political and military objective was to
stop Akbar from winning and
remain independent himself.  These were two different objectives.
Now, the Battle of Haldighati was shot in
a day for 6-7 hours using a 6-hour battery.
Historians are unable to agree on
who won. Some people say that
Akbar won, some people say that it was a draw;
no one won. So how do we decide
what happened?
How to decide is very simple. Who was
successful in achieving his objective? Did Akbar
destroy Maharana Pratap's army? Did
Akbar make Maharana Pratap surrender? Did
Akbar kill Maharana Pratap?
No, he could not do all these things.
Maharana Pratap remained independent even after this meeting.
He did
not accept Akbar as his Maharaja.
He could not force Maharana Pratap to accept Akbar as his Maharaja and
hand over his secretary to Akbar. So,
if we talk about these two different objectives, Maharana Pratap
accomplished his objective
and Akbar
failed in his objective. So,
if we examine this further,
Maharana Pratap  He was successful and Akbar was
unsuccessful, so I absolutely believe,
Babu, my Babu, my energy, it is very
clear that the outcome of this battery
was in favor of Maharana Pratap and not Akbar, it is in
favor of the Mughal, these are simple things and nothing else,
so let's see some more questions, Ad
Lut
Rajvardhan asks, what are
your views on Dayanand, Dayanand Saraswati and Arya Samaj, see, I have
not studied Dayanand Saraswati and
Arya Samaj much, but as much as I
know, I understand
that Dayanand Saraswati is very much against idol worship,
he had
broken many idols
in Varanasi, but what is the problem with these people, is idol
worship a
bad thing,
why do they want to reform Hinduism,
all these people, look at the ship,
you want to call Hindu sea as if it is a
Hindu evil which
needs to be reported, hey, remind yourself brother,
I do
not understand that these people are
against idol worship, does idol worship
kill anyone, does idol worship cause
any harm to anyone  Hey
everyone has their own style of worship to
follow religion some people
worship idols what is wrong in that
brother so
this Dayanand Saraswati is a reformer who
wanted to stop idol worship why
brother what is the need you don't do it if you like it
why do you post others some
break idols of others so this is
criminal reformative lake some people say
we have to call Hinduism we have to do good
why do we have to do it brother use our other
religions which are reliance not
religion go and remind the religion if you want to
report someone
why do you keep Ekta Samaj here so sir this is my
problem I have
not read so much about Dayanand Saraswati or
Arya Samaj but all this is
from the reformative movement and their thing is always that
stop idol worship
you should not do it on the phone so I like it
why do you follow others so this is what I have to
say I get so angry about it there is
MP3 of
9th May they ask that we are powerful is India
in nuclear war  There has never been an affair with Indians.
Only one
country has done it on nuclear war till date,
which is the United States of America. China
attacked Japan for 2 minutes and many people died in that.
After that, no country has
indulged in nuclear war. But
after India, India definitely comes close to
doing nuclear war.
If you look at the official figures available in the West, if you
look at Western publications like Foreign Policy Magazine,
Foreign Affairs Magazine, there are many recent job
vacancies in them, it is said
that India has around 120
nuclear weapons. These people say so
and India also has delivery systems like
ballistic missiles, short-term ballistic missiles,
medium-term ballistic missiles,
long-range ballistic missiles, short-range
medium-range ballistic missiles,
intercontinental range ballistic missiles,
India already has 20 of them and this is continuously
developing and
good missiles are being made and they are becoming an example.
And submarine launched missiles are also available.
India has short-range missiles, perhaps
medium-range missiles and the British might also be developing them, they might have already developed them.
All these things are
not done transparently,
so India has a very good capacity for
nuclear power. India
also has bombers. If you talk about the multi-role
fighter plane, then
this is the profile which can
deliver nuclear weapons.
From this point on the BrahMos missile,
India has a very good capability related to
nuclear trade. If we talk about
three different delivery mechanisms,
ballistic missiles, senior deliveries, now
clearly nuclear weapons, and submarines,
nuclear weapons. India has the entire nuclear
trade. India
also has nuclear submarines. So, India is
quite capable in this nuclear war field, it is
quite powerful, and this is a very
good thing for us. This is a very
good deterrent for India, which will tell our enemies that
you cannot cross certain 11 specific red
lines of India.
Also, if you close that red light,
anything can happen. So, India is quite
powerful. Air India's technology is quite
good. We have cruise missiles like
Swift and it is very auspicious. But sonic
cruise missiles, supersonic missiles and some more
cruise missiles are being developed.
And perhaps we can also
deposit nuclear missiles or nuclear weapons from satellites.
Perhaps now, Sir, we have a lot of
options. So, India is quite
powerful in nuclear war. Let's
ask some more questions. Let's take the
project and ask whether Akhand like
Nepal's trust was present. Battery plays some role
in your parents' can have. Look, not every country
can play geopolitics. Every
country has some important significance
in politics and what its importance is
depends on its
geographical location. If you
talk about Nepal, it is a country sandwiched between India and Tibet.
And right now, you know that Tibet is under the
occupation of China. So, it means that there is
a very important
match between India and China.  It is a symbolic location, so
due to its geographical location,
Nepal plays a very important role as a buffer
state. Earlier, there used to be an active buffer state between India and China,
but our great Prime Minister Mr. Nehru did
nothing to stop Tibet from being handed over to China, so
now
Nepal is a buffer state between India and China,
and right now China is trying to make a lot of inroads
in Nepal. As
you know, it keeps coming in the news a lot.
Right now, the Communist Party is ruling in Nepal.
Communism and the Communist Party play a very
important role in Nepali politics as well. So,
due to all these things, Nepal has become a very
important country in the contest of the dynamics of India and China. Even though it is a
small country, it has a very important
role in politics.
Anand Tripathi asks, there is an
Indian, a theist considered Hindu. Sir, see,
if you talk about the philosophy of Hinduism, then the
Nine Makers School is a successful institution, it
comes under Hinduism, many
come under it, due to which it  There is Charvaka, Gautam
Jain, Bodh, Doctrine, Yoga, Numbers,
Vidhansabha, and perhaps one more,
I have been examined at this time, but there are many
schools of thought in it. Then there is the
Jain school of thought, in
which God is not considered as a mother. Bodh school of thought
also has the role of God, but the
role of mother is taken by the mother.
If you talk about Mimansa, then there is no
creator god in it, but there is the
law of karma in it, which keeps the entire universe
running autonomously. And if you
talk about cyclone, then there is the full thick lipstick school
of art, in this there is nothing about God, Karma,
but still all these
school certificates come under Hinduism.
Hinduism is a part of our old religious belief, all these
and in this, if they are
theists, then it is
four bike, that is, Jains
or people with aircraft, all these
people, while fighting this war, they
believe in God, but still
it comes under the Hindu category, that is why
India  There are lies in them. Those who are atheists are
also Hindus. There is nothing like Hinduism,
if you adopt it then I will
not consider you a Hindu like it happens
in foreign relations. There is nothing like this in Hinduism. There is nothing like this
in Hinduism. Even
if you do not believe in God,
you can still live a religious lifestyle. That is
why only Indians consider it completely
Hindu.
One
important reason for the loot was BJP. Make India and Hindu Rashtra.
Now only these two BJPs can answer this question.
If you look at the pattern of the last seven-eight years
of BJP, they
completely believe in our Constitution. The BJP
government believes
in our conditions. They
also consider the conditions as a holy book. They also
believe in it in many other circles and
Mahatma Gandhi is worshipped a lot.
So if you look at the pattern of the last seven-eight years, it does
not seem that they
want to make India a Hindu Rashtra very soon. But there can be reasons for this also. It is a
very complete thing
if Win India a Hindu Rashtra.  If we
declare it, then who knows what
other countries might do. Other countries, like
America and the West, are completely anti-
Hindu. So, if your long-term
objective is to make India a Hindu nation, then
in the short term you will have to remain silent
about it. This is also a
possibility.
But if you ask me immediately
if BJP will make India a Hindu nation, then
immediately in the next 10-20
years, it does not seem possible at all.
If they have a long-term plan, they will
keep that plan very secret and when the time comes, then they will probably reveal it.
I think this is how the leadership
works, this is how the politics works. It was
looted,
looted. You are one who asks why did not take
socialism obscene and Indian socialism.
Look at socialism, it is quite
balanced, soft Marxism in the eyes.
And if you have to
select it, if you have to make it successful, then first of all
you
need a prosperous society, which is
not only a prosperous society, it is a very weak
society and a very rough society.
But socialism cannot work. If you
look at any country which has been a security school,
for example, if you look at China, which was a
very
complete country like India used to be, recently
then China has
not created its economic system through social science. They said that it is complete
from the past and through state and centralized planning
and they have achieved economic growth.
If you compare Vietnam,
they have also added centralized
economy, centralized plant economy and the
state control and there is a lot of capitalism in it. These countries
where there is socialism, they are
not completely socialism and they are also
centrally planned and all those societies were
already prosperous. For this, it seems
that it has been successful. Europe
was already very prosperous and now they have implemented
socialist policies there,
so it seems that
it is not something that was already
prosperous. Now India  And India was
very broken after 1947.
Whatever wealth Britain had to extract, it took it
all out of India. So if India had to
stand on its feet again, then
India needed not socialism but
strong central plant economics and
Indian economy and capitalist
hybrid system. This was needed and
Nehruji introduced Fabian socialism.
Nehruvian rate of growth of 2% every
year. That is why Indian socialism is spread
because of Nehruji and nothing else.
If he had used any other
method, perhaps the
story of India's growth would have been different.
But friend Ugi wanted to
experiment with this socialism on India, so he did that.
Now see what the
result was.
Once
Soham asks, how do you think about this era, this
influential and present as it was in the
past century and works its rule in
current geopolitics.
Today, there is not much influence there. They also
call themselves Great Britain, the
United Kingdom, but there is nothing left
there.  But
whatever the solar child is, what it is, is
their economy and they have built their career on the pretext of the
money they have looted from the whole world, especially from India, in the last two-three years, so that much
greatness is left with them, London is the
hub of global finance, all the global corporations have their
offices there and is a very important part of the global financial system,
so after so much time, child, you do
not have any other influence, they essentially have a
state of the US
like Australia, New Zealand, it is
also a tax base, when
all the English speaking countries are from the US and
today and among them, Uttar Pradesh, the
biggest among them, does
not have any special military, they have nuclear
weapons, but
for the delivery system of nuclear weapons, from all their missiles, they used to have
Polaris,
which is in my house today
and now there will be some more missiles, probably
within an inch of them and the man who is there
Deployment is done as per what America says, in
this song it is essential that it has become just
an American puppet and nothing else
and
these people talk big in politics but they do not have any
significant rules so
today UK's biggest role in the world is that it is an
American puppet and nothing else, till the time the
loot is not washed away, let
me take some more questions,
okay again the same and put one more, that is the
trillions looted by JDU, you have
hundreds of years, India UK has almost the same
GDP growth, meanwhile the
question is that if you
look at the calculations of this, then their
estimate is that UK looted
approximately 4.5 trillion dollars worth of
money from India, according to today's user rates,
so where did all this money go,
I do
know about this, the
founders of this university, on the
one
hand they were East India Company officials,
they returned a lot of money to India and
He
invested that money
in the United States. A lot of it went into university
foundations.
If you follow the money trail, you'll see that
some 455 trillion dollars that was looted from India has been
distributed all over the Western world,
not just in the UK. Now, some of
their lead families, which have been there
since the time of the East India Company, are
settled in many different countries, and that
money has also been distributed in different places. So, the
entire Western world benefited from all this money looted from India, especially
your valid
families and your close friends,
but a lot of it went into infrastructure,
universities, palaces,
and many different
financial systems were crushed. So, the
maturity money that was looted from India has been
distributed all over the Western world. It's quite good.
USB is today. So, if we
attack the East India Company and if we
defeat them, and I also have the East.  We will
get very little money back which Arun had stolen. This is
so much money that we have forgotten because all the money has been
stashed in different places. So
this is the matter of trillions of rupees
and it will be pristine in different places.
If we press it back then it will take a lot of
time and we do not have any such
solution to take it
back to the office. So the solution for us is
that we have to work a lot on our cars again, we have to
work very hard and bring ourselves
back to the big economic position
which we had in the historical role.
We have to do the same with our hard work. Right now
Varun Singh asks that if there is any
political, social and cultural situation in the
Middle East, then oil was never found there and this is a
very good question and today the Middle-East is a
very important and very prosperous
geographical region of the
world and one of its simple reasons is that
so much oil is found there and because of that oil,
they have become so prosperous.  They have
so much money that if this
oil had not been found there, they would have had no
status at all today. They would have been a very
backward and ancient region of the world.
If oil had not been found there, simple
things. Even now,
many different new sources of oil have
emerged and intense. Today, the
United States has become the world's largest oil producer. The development of waste
oil filters is declining. So, for this, they are
slowly going into crisis.
Their monopoly on oil will be lost
and even some other
sources of energy will also emerge. I will also make it
sustainable and from there, 600-800 sources. So,
for this, these people are now going into crisis mode
and their entire lifestyle, their
entire way of life, is going to change completely
in some 10, 20, 30 years. If
oil had not been found there, then it would have been a very backward and
ancient region of the world. It is
simple. It was
looted and
washed away. Why are you asking Sir?  Please tell us about the
origin of Bengalis, it is
related to returning springs, very nice to
see from here, Bengalis are also from India, so I mean,
Bengal, which we call Bengal today,
its original name was Vanga Pradesh,
from Vyang Vyang it became Baghban and from Bengal it became Bengal, the
British named this place
Bengal, so its original name was
Vanga Pradesh and perhaps a
few thousand years ago it was Rang Pradesh, perhaps
and as you know that in Mahabharata,
Karna became the Maharaja of Anga Pradesh, so from a
very old history,
Bengal belongs to a very old, very old history
and the origin is the same as the original of India, the
Bengalis are its region, the
people of Bengal are not a different race or there is nothing different like that,
India is these people and
Arjun of India is very very old, if you
talk about your animated version, then some of the
male patrilineal lineages of India, you people, the
male lineages of India are about 60
thousand years old and if you talk about the male lineages,
matrilineal  Onion juice is
definitely coming from 6570, so India is the
oldest
arthropod analysis and tough vaccine and some
countries phase ago when
Homo sapiens was notified and gradually they
went to the East and established their base in all these pertinents in India, so the
first point of sale
counters is in India itself and everyone went away from India and
migrated to other places,
but the people who were in India definitely stayed in India, so
this is the original genetic of India
and Junaid and
Bengali people are also a part of it, so in short, these are the
Bengali people and in which is the region of
India, these people are nothing but
swastikas and it is possible to
reverse all the happiness depends upon
India, all the best one thousand years and
take India back to its most glorious
taste, one drops a peak, it is
not possible to reverse anything more, whatever has happened has happened
and there
must be some reason for it,
and this is the reason  It was said that India
was not so united, so we have to learn from whatever happened in history,
we have to learn this lesson from it
and apply it so that
such things do not happen again in the future.
Whatever happened was very bad in the last
1000 years, we cannot reverse it, it is
not possible to reverse it, but we can
redevelop ourselves, we can
unify ourselves again, we have to develop ourselves again,
we have to impress science and technology and again our culture,
our civilization has to be
brought to that level again in the next 10, 20, 50 years
and again India will become glorious, defeated and
extraordinary if we all work together on this, then the
right
word is mystery, how old is it
compared to India's situation,
then rulers of various appearances in times
of knowledge and way
teaching
pit, firstly if we
write history then it is some 5,000 years
old,
history is 5,000 years old, now if we
talk about India then  It is at least 10,000 years old.
If you
read about the
Indus Valley sites, for
example, it is at least nine to ten thousand years
old. And many discover it is very
clear that India has the oldest history.
If we talk about any classical civilization, we will
talk about Egypt,
we will talk about Sapsid Baby,
after China and if we talk about India, then
India is the oldest among all of them
and this civilisation is 10,000 plus years
old, it is still existing, it is still existing, so if we
talk about antiquity, we will talk about today,
which is not compared to
India, India is the oldest civilization, there is no
doubt in it at all,
so now after superiority in it, we will talk
about knowledge and wells, so
brother,
if you talk about geographical area, then if we talk
only about the Arappan phase of India,
if we talk about our history, only
Harappan phase, Saptasindhu phase, then the
geographical area was of Harappan phase.  Even if
you add Egypt and Mesopotamia, it will still fall
short. Our Yogaraj has taken such a huge area
and it was a very developed
and powerful phase of separation. There were
big cities, there were small settlements and there were
small villages too,
but all of them were closed and were built and
highly developed and the entire system was of the
best civilization and there was very high level of
architecture and engineering, hydro
engineering and many other things. So it is
clear that this was a very scientific and
technological advancement phase of
civilization. Some parts of
India had advanced 5,000 years ago.
If you talk about advancement, then
think about the knowledge required to build all this.
Such a high level of architecture, such a high
level of scientific and technological
progress cannot happen without knowledge.
If you talk about respect, then you
see big 13 minutes from there, for which
definitely and engineering know how.
But our engineering iron was no less than that
and our engineer Noah was before him
and it is such a big civilization
whose geographical area is so big
and so highly developed, then imagine
that the wealth would also be so much and if you want to read the welcome
page then you should
look at the research of Angus Medicine, which is
publicly available, it is only a
part of the last two thousand years, but in that also it
is very clear that India's GDP is at least 100% of the
total GDP of the whole world, even at
that time Egypt
was quite advanced and during the time of Roman Iraq, if there was a
small correction in the
GDP of India, then it is a magic player
that India's
historical status has been that it has
always been the most advanced in everything, in knowledge, in wealth
and if you
go further back, then it will increase even more and India's share in the
entire world's GDP will increase, it is very
clear that
this has been the historical role of India, the
gift of meeting the most advanced is not something special, it is in comparison
and  If you talk about waste,
you portray it so much as waste, then you will definitely portray it as waste. The
western world
believes that their civilization,
support, qualification, and according to them, Egypt and the
Middle East, their
original image of the Middle East and
research, these three are their sources, so they consider this gift as
a source of their civilization, so
for this, it will have to be exaggerated, it will have to be
exaggerated, so this is a
simple reason why the waste portrays you so
advancedly, let's have
some more questions,
Dungar Singh Chauhan says, please tell us
about Srinivasa Ramanujan, see, Srinivasa
Ramanujan was a natural
talent in mathematics, I don't see from here, and a
mathematician is naturally talented,
but
normally what happens is that mathematicians
study in a step by step progression,
so they study from school
to college, then college
to Sheffield University, and then in research career,
Srinivasa Ramanujan, there was
no such structured study.  He
danced on his own, internet diabetes and the
Indian education system, this
education system almost
destroyed him. Now if
I have so much talent
or if someone is so strong in any field, then does it
mean
that his talent will decrease in the second phase?
Now Ramanujan's talent was
not only in mathematics but in anything else.
He failed in English and social service and
in everything in school and
college but he made his orbit in the match.
But the Indian education system is such
that you have to pass in everything.
If you do not pass everything, then you will pass. So
this system is so bad
that it almost destroyed Ramanujan
but fortunately he survived and
a British, that is, Mr. Hardy,
Raman ji had written a letter to him. When G.H.
Hardy showed this letter, he understood
that this was a very high, lovely high level thing
and then he
called Ramanujan to London. Then what  The Western
world discovered Raman ji and
Ramanujan remained active for only a few years Ajay
Masterbation Eventually he
died at a very young age but his
contributions were incredible
inspirations and are still very
useful
especially for string theory and
in the black hole project extra quantum
discovery that is still useful so he was a very
super talent in mathematics he was one in huck one
hundred years and definition of that so that is in
short but Srinivas Ramanujan was
very talented and very high level
mathematician that a
Shravan just
now ok next question are the Nepali
support of Indian civilization is
absolutely the people of Nepal are absolutely
a part of Indian culture and Indian civilization there is no
doubt in this
if you look at Nepal and Sri Lanka then all these are
part of our civilization today though there
are definitely different countries but there is a huge difference between civilization and country
so country is the best
for even there the concept of nation state which is the
system that is prevalent today  There has been a
Westphalian nation-states, according to that,
India, Sri Lanka and Nepal are different countries with
different nations, but that civilization is the same
and the people are also the same, for
me we are very similar,
our ancestors were the same
and our culture and our Jor
culture is also the same, so this is definitely a
part of the culture of Nepal in the people of Nepal,
Shravan
Just
and
Soro asks,
Namaste, the way you
made a full documentary on sugar mines, so on
which subject are you working on making such a documentary,
please make one on science also,
I have some projects going on, it will take
some time, right now
I will not announce the
configuration of what I am working on,
but those choris will all be released step by
step and I am absolutely confident that it will be useful to
you, everyone is
interested, next that guy times right,
so I am definitely working on some things,
but it will take some time, okay brother, it is a
matter of quality, the quality should be good,
what I have been doing till now  I'm doing a
live stream and
answering as many questions as I can and
releasing small tips for them, but I have to
change my strategy. I'm
also monitoring this channel and
creating high-quality documents. So,
research is currently underway on it.
Venturi will implement it, which will take
some time. I
invented the Times Right, and I'll definitely
build it on science as well.
Definitely, it's
Lut and Mr. Vansh. What have you seen?
India Switch of Prime Minister feature.
I haven't seen it. I can only say
that I hope our
future leaders are
good and their quality should
always increase a little bit every time so that
our feature becomes stronger and stronger. For this,
we have to understand what leadership is. What is
dealership?
What is the problem today? No one knows what
leadership is. What is dealership?
Leadership is a very important thing
in everyone's life, if we understand it.  Did you understand
or not that it is
real and then what is the leadership
then the future of our country will not be so good,
so I hope that our future
Prime Ministers, you become President,
whoever it is, in the future only our
government system can change,
definitely, so I hope that our
future leadership will be very good, let us
ask you that a Chinese and so
strong man would not talk about Pakistan
land,
good west, very good question,
if China is so powerful then
why doesn't it occupy Pakistan,
see, it is already
ruling Pakistan,
you are the CEA because the Pakistani Army
which rules Pakistan is
definitely the stomach of China, so China is
getting all the benefits of
controlling Pakistan, so
why should it go and because brother, if you
go and keep Pakistan under your eyes then
you will have to dominate Pakistan,
why would you ask, take it upon yourself, just do
remote control and as far as governance
is concerned and all those things are there in Pakistan
Leave this on the front,
why do you have to enter, it is simple,
they are getting liquor benefits without making Pakistan the
Governor, see, there is another
Vindhyachal Bhawan, the country, Prithvi, win-win
situation for China, because what has to be done,
okay bye, you will do it, then you will have to sell your army,
your ministry,
administrator, you will have to sell the entire state
of the country, whatever problem has to be
solved, why do you have to do it brother, there is
no need, that is why China does not comment further
and only controls Pakistan through a series
of proxy,
this is a win-win situation, Pakistan is
looted,
so let's take some more questions,
Priya says that India is
completely self-reliant,
India is self-reliant to some
extent, I do not believe that India is
completely offline tech, if you talk about general production
and through this, whatever
weapons we have, or we import a lot of these weapons
from different countries, so
in this we do not have celluloid, now we
also import a lot of food grains  We
import food items from different countries,
so we are
self-reliant in that too. Today, such a situation exists
because of the fact that all the countries are
not one hundred percent superior in anything,
so India is in the same situation, but if
you compare China, they manufacture everything separately on
their own, so China is
very good at a high level, only fashion and
champion, and
they import only basic materials
which are not available with them,
and you import rare earth and some minerals
extra but support finished products,
so this has been a very successful
system of China, which India should also actually
adopt immediately, so I do
not believe that India is completely self-reliant at this time,
but India is definitely progressing
quite well, it has happened, it has happened,
and let us not ask for details on that, and
good for understanding leadership, Vicky,
about leadership, Madam, I have
not seen any good picture today.  Till now some
books talk about leadership
but it talks about corporate conduct,
leadership in corporate conduct, that is fake
leadership but if you are a project manager then
how do you do everything, you do nothing, then all
this is not there and
corporate leadership management and management
is not leadership, measurements are just serving
for a price, so unfortunately I have read any
good book on leadership, I have
not found any till date, unfortunately so
if you do not understand leadership then you will have to
read history and
historical figures.  You will have to study the lives of great
leaders and
historical figures, whoever you like,
whoever you consider as
historical figures, study their lives, through that
you might
understand a little about leadership, but
I don't know anything specific
from which you can learn leadership, unfortunately I
lost
a new
Krish Bahra says that don't think calling
Bhatkeshwar these various Islamic invaders
distrustful, today Indian society is the best
Indian Islam peacefully and for two thousand
of Muslims should ask you for help in this,
brother, which Muslim scholars
fought with Tarkeshwar, that I think Hudgens
definitely
spoke against tax, at that time Afghanistan was a
part of India, but the
senior Islamic invaders were not
Christian inverts, they were not Hindu in image,
what is disrespectful in that,
brother, it is a simple fact, the research rocky, nothing which is
respectful  Even these callings of
invaders mirror, I keep them horny
because it is okay with the morning
or if you do matters after that or
those girls should talk to Mughals, all this is just a matter of the
field, so I call them Turkish eunuchs,
but some people call it Islamic
invasions, which is absolutely unpleasant, there is nothing
disrespectful in it, according to
me,
and if some Muslim
soldiers had fought against them after hearing this, then it is a
good thing to fight because they are from India,
but these invasions are definitely
because of Turkey, and Islamic invasion, there is nothing about
business pet in it,
Ban Chatterjee asks, who will start India vs
Pakistan, there is an order, breakup of
India with evil, brother, this should have been done a few years
ago, today if you see, where will the
place be, then China has
more money than India,
if they compare China, if they
compare Pakistan, then we
cannot match that bad, today in 199,
if we should do this, we should do it  If it was so, it would have been
successful but today China's juice
pending power is much more than India.
Today, even if we bribe
Pakistan, and China opens that bag and
sees easily, then it will keep doubling itself.
Therefore, today this technique of Tata ji will
not work, it should have been done earlier.
Vineet asks about secularism
in India, what was the subjective
secularism? It is a philosophy, cardiology,
what ever, it means only one thing that it is anti-
Hindu religion. Secularism,
these people say that this is their Hindustan and to
save Bharat, this thing was
imported in India, but India does
not need confirmation. It is a foreign
ideology or a foreign concept. The
historical meaning of secularism has been separation
of change and state. There is no church in India.
We have
not seen these till recently, now it is coming up differently, so
what is the need of secondary education in India
and what is the need to fit this breast cancer
in India?  There is a need but it has happened now,
we have been implementing it for the last 70 years, 60
years, so
now it has become a very integral part
of India and it has become
a high ideal, it is a look-alike and
you become the same, circular, I do
not believe in secularism at all, thank you, no
doubt, so
let's have some more questions, it has happened,
okay, okay, by adding a period of one thousand
years back, Afghanistan, Pakistan,
Bangladesh, North East India, hypocrisy,
what is and Vivo, body, and of Hinduism,
petrol, polythene, this is definitely a
possibility, if we continue like this, then
Hindus will be finished because the
Indian State, the Indian Governor, the
Indian
Establishment, all of them are anti-Hindu and
all the laws are anti-Hindu, the Constitution of India
is anti-Hindu and all the
government policies have also become anti-Hindu, so the
curative effect of all this is
different, there is a defect in Hinduism in the same day  It is
gradually being ignored and this
cunning which is happening, Hindu saint Kabir is
also accelerating, if it continues like this then
in the next hundred years, this year,
Hindu religion will become extinct, that is
definitely a strong possibility, just
like Roman polytheism is gone,
it is the possibility of emerging,
Yogi asks what is Thomas positive
conservative science, see there are a
lot of mathematical calculations in astrology, so
definitely there is some
sound action of science in the country, but whatever its
principles are, I cannot say whether they are so scientific or not,
on the face of it, it is
scientific in it, but it is unscientific, they say that
some planets have some effect on
our lives, I am a scientist, I have
never done astrology, so maybe
I am not the right person to ask about it,
maybe there will be something in astrology, but
I do not know about it, I have never done
astrology, I
understand astronomy, I understand science,
Android Astro Physics  I understand I
review Additional District
but I have never studied astrology so that's why
inside the fee pocket I think it is
not that scientific but I am also
mistaken because I have never
studied it in detail in the morning also I am not the
right person to ask West to Ujjain
once
so let's take a couple of questions from
Shravan
by this line President in Africa what
will invest I repeated the previous song again
140 channel back China
is investing in Africa for raw material there is a
lot of raw material from minerals, there is
school, there is gold and many
other Roberts which are used in electronics, there is
shell and timber and many other things
and Africa
151 points touch content based on 72825 century
and they want to increase their sphere of influence there which is
politically if
you want to pass some resolution in the urine then
you need numbers if you make
good investments in Africa and
keep them happy then you will get their WhatsApp so
these are all different reasons
for which  China is very serious
about these investments, so for this
China is so interested in Africa,
let me take a couple of questions,
Anand Mohan is asking us about the European
nuclear treasure found in
India, it's amazing, I've heard about it,
but I've never seen it before. Some
people say that
nuclear radiation is found in some Indus Valley-sized structure, brother.
I've never seen anything like this.
Who tweeted this, and which
instrument did they use?
It was some other counter, and how much did
they get a relation
order? So,
only some
specific information is not available about this, who
tweeted this, what was his name,
how did he delete it,
so I think all this is a mushrooming rumor,
until I get hard evidence,
I
can't give any opinion about it. Unfortunately, I've
also searched about it, but I've never had
any hand in David Villa. Solid, looks
like it's just a room and will remain. Maybe
this
MP3
Bluetooth word
loot.
New Delhi Uttam says that
these days Japanese attack on 370, you know, the Japanese army became
active in the Second World War to
invest and occupy India
and with them was the Indian National Army of
Subhash Chandra Bose, so they
invaded North India through this, they
invested in Nagaland and
sold their skin in Manipur
and it was very important but also the Battle
of Ko and the Battle of Imphal and some other
battles from Moirang information in Manipur,
there was a pattern of theirs and the Battle of Rat
Hill also took place, Manipur was
quite intense and
Japan lost all these battles and from there
Japan's
sequence of defeat in the Second World War started,
so their objective was to
remove the British from India, you should
occupy India completely there, Japan wanted to occupy India and then
they wanted to occupy India, so this was their
personal and then they had
reached so far away from Japan that their supply
lines and  All this became very worrying and
because of this they lost all these Petis and then the
complete retreat of Manchurian started
from here and there was
improvement in short but Japanese attack in
North East India on
Ajay,
so let me take another question,
Jhalal
Loot Manoj is asking whether this termite is good for
India and Shirdi soil something new for
democracy is good for India,
but democracy is an
Indian system,
if you talk about the history of India, if you
talk about Mahajanapada Iraqi, then
how were the democracies in India at that time, if you talk about Harappan Iraqi, then
there also it seems that
our system was democratic because there is
no balance of any king Maharaj in it, there is no such
bead or autocratic
system, so it is clear that even at that time there were
Democratic leaders in India, so what is
said in the West that democracy is divided from Greece,
this is absolutely a
point collection, this currency is Indian
system, but this
historical democratic system in India was
different from today's system,
so in India  There were kings and emperors too,
but democracy was said from here, at that
time, it was a hybrid system of India and
today the system of democracy in India has become
an inferior and weak system.
Because of this, more divisions are happening in India
and this is not good for India. So, India
needs to find another system. Perhaps the
historical democratic system of India
needs to be discovered and
invested in it, but today's
system is not so good that
you can use these other systems and India is
not getting any benefit from it. India is facing this
obscene problem. So, I think India needs a
better system now, more
democratic and strong and a system
which will be good for India. India
needs that. So, let me take one last question for
today.
Shashank says and asks, what do you think how
Lord Krishna would have dealt with the
situation in our country, in which country
is right on this
topic. If you read the
history of India during the time of Mahabharata, then Shri Krishna said  He did it
and he must have made a lot of efforts to
unify everyone.
He tried very hard with the pride of negotiations
so that he could avoid the possibility of war,
but these negotiations failed. Then
he told the Pandavas that you will have to fight.
This was his
philosophy:
try to avoid war as much as possible, make every effort, and
if these efforts fail, then
definitely go to war. He believed that
his decision would be successful.
What would he do today? If Krishna had
come to India today, he would have seen that India is a very
divided country, there are many problems in India,
and the Indian government
system is very weak. So, perhaps he would have done
something like this while reporting to the system. And there is
no question of war, it is a good thing at this time, but
his face would have been like this.
India has become a very unrighteous country. So,
perhaps he would have promoted religion
in India, then he would have done something like this. Now all I
can say is that Shri Krishna is the incarnation of Shri
Krishna, so
perhaps Shri Krishna would have done something like this.  So
let's ask one last question abroad, what should
India do, interview Kulwinder Cold
War, what should India do at this time, right now
a new code word type situation is being created, the
entire geopolitical real alignment is happening
in the world,
WhatsApp India Dubai, what
should India do, it is very simple,
India has to strengthen itself
economically and militarily and internally,
today India is facing a lot of internal problems, there is a lot of division in India, there are many
problems of infiltration, many
Bangladeshi Rohingyas have entered everywhere
and many such things are going on, so India has to pay a
lot of attention to its internal problems, it has to do an
internal strike, India has to
form a trust as soon as possible, it has to increase its economy, at least
10-12 crore, the first
step India will have to do is 150 crore and it will have to do as much as possible as soon as possible,
you
need to increase the economic growth, you should
be happy with this, that is why India has to strengthen
itself with military along with it  We have to increase
our diplomatic juice, we have to
teach them through trains and India has to do all this,
if we do all this well and in a very
good systematic way, then we will emerge from this cold war as a
very strong country,
so India should do this,
now today's session is over, the remaining
1 hour and 15 minutes have passed, so thank you very
much for attending this, please
tell me in the comments how you liked this section,
this is the first Hindi section in Hindi, did you like it or did you
dislike it, please
give me your feedback and I will definitely do it
and if anyone has
any suggestion for improvement, then I will
try to improve it, so thank you very much,
Dhaniya to all of you and I will definitely meet you in the next session,
thank you very much, good
good night, bye bye